# KARRA SAI SARATH

## JAVA DEVELOPER

saisarath88@gmail.com | 8328512611 | Bangalore

#### **SUMMARY**

Competent Java developer with over 4 plus years of experience in developing and implementing Java-based applications. Well-versed in Java and core Spring concepts, including OOP, Java 8, Dependency Injection, Collections, and Exception Handling etc. Knowledgeable in developing Single Page Applications (SPA) utilizing Angular, HTML, CSS and TypeScript technologies. Collabrates effeciently with other teams to deliver solutions on time and meet project deadlines and continuously learning to grow and enhance my technical abilities. Experienced in working with Agile methodology.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : Java, HTML, CSS, SQL and Typescript

Frameworks : Spring Boot, Hibernate and Angular

Tools : Oracle SQL Developer, VS Code, Eclipse, Postman, IntelliJ, Tortoise Git

OS : Windows

**Aglie Tools** : Azure Devops Server

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Technology Analyst, Infosys Limited**

May 2024 - Present

Client : COLT Project : COLT ONLINE

- Involved in requirement gathering, thorough analysis, and the creation of both high-level and detailed low-level designs.
- Developed RESTful controllers to create endpoints and service layers to incorporate business logic for respective end points.
- Implemented DAO Layers leveraging leveraging Spring Data JPA to interact with databases for data persistence and retrieval.
- Implemented Centralized Exception handling for Rest end points using RestControllerAdvice.
- Investigated and resolved bugs identified during integration testing of various application modules.
- Acquired Knowledge of Spring Security with JWT based Authentication while working on related tasks.
- Investigated application and Kafka logs to identify the root cause of unprocessed records.

#### **Associate Software Engineer, Mphasis Limited**

March 2022 - May 2024

Client : FEDEX Project : CREW PAY

- Participated in requirement gathering, and the creation of both high-level and low-level designs.
- Developed RESTful controllers to create endpoints and service layers to incorporate business logic for respective end points.
- Developed repository layers leveraging Spring Data JPA to interact with databases for data persistence and retrieval.
- Implemented centralized application logging using Spring AOP and Interceptors for HTTP request/response logging to facilitate detailed tracking of API communication.
- Gained knowledge of concepts like Thread safety, synchronization and Executors while working on related tasks.
- Developed user interface (UI) screens to display pilot information and services for making HTTP calls to backend endpoints for retrieving the data.

Client : FEDEX Project : CREW PAY

- Involved in requirement gathering, thorough analysis, and the creation of both high-level and detailed low-level designs.
- Investigated and resolved bugs identified during integration testing of various application modules.
- Engaged in the implementation of RESTful API endpoints and service layers to integrate business logic for respective endpoints.
- Contributed to the creation of repository layers using Spring Data JPA to facilitate data persistence and retrieval from databases.
- Assisted in designing initial UI mockups and wireframes in Figma to visualize data presentation and user workflows.
- Aided in the development of user interface (UI) screens and services for making HTTP calls to backend endpoints, enabling data retrieval and display on the UI.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **B.E - Electronics and Communication Engineering**

June 2016 - May 2020

Sree Vidyanikethan Engineering College - Tirupati, India.

#### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

- Languages: English.
- **Certifications:** Mphasis Certified Java Microservices and Angular, Infosys Certified Spring Boot Developer.